<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>geospatial on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</title>
    <link>/tags/geospatial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in geospatial on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/geospatial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fairfax County Workforce</title>
      <link>/findings/01-workforce-in-ffx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/01-workforce-in-ffx/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4 { text-align: center; }  Approach This page characterizes the Fairfax County workforce. To do this, we used two datasets to better understand the population of individuals with job locations in Fairfax County. LEHD Origin-Destination Employment Statistics (LODES) data provide worker race, ethnicity, education, gender, and industry data at census block group level. We retrieved these characteristics from the 2017 LODES data, which we summarized at the workplace county level to provide an overview of Fairfax County’s workforce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairfax County Residents&#39; Employment Characteristics</title>
      <link>/findings/02-ffx-residents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/02-ffx-residents/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4 { text-align: center; }  Approach This documents provides baseline census tract-level visualizations for characteristics of Fairfax County residents who are in the labor force. Along with sociodemographic characteristics like workers’ age, ethnicity, level of education, and median income, we also consider how long workers residing in different parts of the county have to travel to get to their work site, what industries they work in, and what their occupations are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Areas Vulnerable to Covid-Related Income and Job Loss</title>
      <link>/findings/03-vulnerable-areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/03-vulnerable-areas/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4 { text-align: center; }  Approach This section examines relative vulnerability to COVID-related income and job loss in Fairfax County, VA at the census tract-level. Identifying vulnerable areas is important to our Fairfax County sponsors as it can help anticipate and prepare for post-pandemic changes. We first examined the total number of initial unemployment filings for the county to understand which areas were most impacted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Employment Areas in Fairfax County</title>
      <link>/findings/04-emerging-areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/04-emerging-areas/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4 { text-align: center; }  Approach One of our project objectives was to identify areas in Fairfax County with current and emerging employment and business opportunities. Identification of areas with business and employment opportunities can help county authorities formulate policies supporting the growth of these areas, as well as to lean from these areas to improve other parts of the county that currently do not attract many business initiatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Network Analysis to Study Fairfax County Job Flows</title>
      <link>/findings/05-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/05-networks/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4 { text-align: center; }  Approach We employed network analysis to understand the relationships between where Fairfax County residents work and reside. This is important to our sponsors because changes in commuting dynamics due to the pandemic have implications on transportation, housing, and infrastructure policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining Employee Flows Into Fairfax County</title>
      <link>/findings/06-inflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/06-inflows/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3, h4 { text-align: center; }  Approach To prepare for an analysis of Fairfax County job flows, we wanted to better understand the geographic origins of workers who reside in other localities but work in Fairfax County. We examined flows to Fairfax County from within Virginia, from other states, and from counties in other states to identify localities that send the highest number of workers to Fairfax County.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>